RESUME

ANKIT KUMAR

MOBILE: +919472350693

EMAIL:singhankit8212@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Over 3.5 years of technical experience and IT Professional in Web and Mobile API's Development having good knowledge of Vue.js, Laravel, Php, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, MySQL, SQl, Postman, GIT, AWS S3, jira. Ability to work efficiently in both independent and team environments, Quick learner and have ability to meet tight deadlines. To establish myself in computer science industry and find a challenging position so as to use my technical& professional strengths to fulfill the organization goals and objectives together with the accomplishment of my goals of life.

SKILLS

Languages : Vue.js, Laravel, Codeigniter, Php, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, SQL.

Version Controlling: Git

Database : MySQL, PosrgreSQL

Professional Experience

Total experience: More than 3 years in Web development, Progressive WebApp and Mobile API's.

Yes IT Labs : Software Developer (May 2022 - present)

Primary key responsibilities include user interface designing and development and testing in Laravel, Php, and Mobile API's.

Enphase Solar Energy pvt ltd: Junior Engineer Operations (May 2019 - December 2021)

Primary key responsibilities include system support.

CURRENT PROJECT

Name: Buying, Selling Pet

Role: Development using Laravel backend for mobile API's and Stripe Payment use and Admin

for using HTML,CSS,Javascript.

Language: Vue.js, Laravel, GIT, MySQL

Name: Music Player

Role: Development using Laravel backend for mobile API's and using ffmpeg library.

Language: vue.js, Larvel, Html, CSS, JS, GIT, MySQL

Name: Pixy Ecommerce multisite

Role: Development using Laravel backend for mobile API's and Stripe Payment use

Language: Larvel, Html, CSS, JS, AWS S3, MySQL

Name: Optical orders

Role: Development using Codeigniter, payment integration Stripe Payment

Language: Codeigniter, JavaScript, Html, CSS, JS, MySQL

EDUCATIONAL OUALIFICATION

Professional Qualifications:-

MBA (IT) [2020-2022] From GNIT COLLEGE OF

MANAGEMENT, Gr Noida (Affiliated to AKTU formally U.P. Technical University, Lucknow) secured 70%

B.Tech [2015-2020] From ACCURATE INSTITUTE OF

MANAGEMENT AND TECHNOLOGY, Gr Noida (Affiliated to AKTU formally U.P. Technical University, Lucknow) *secured* 72%

Academic Qualifications:-

- 12th [2015] from Balajee inter college, Muzaffarpur, Bihar (BSEB board)
- 10th [2013] from Pristine Children School Muzaffarpur, Bihar (CBSE board.)

STRENGTHS

- Meeting tight deadline with cool head.
- Taking responsibility and ownership for development work.
- High Grasping Power.
- Ability to work in team as well as individual.
- Responsibility and seriousness towards work.
- Good written and verbal communication.